Guide to the Wallace Stegner miscellaneous papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wallace Stegner miscellaneous papers
circa 1944-1992
SC1188
Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-1993
0.5 Linear feet (1 box)
Papers include miscellaneous files about Stanford University, the Wallace Stegner Fellowship in the Stanford University Creative Writing Program, and research and writings about Bernard De Voto.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given by Mary Stegner to Stanford University, Special Collections in June, 1999.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Wallace Earle Stegner was born February 18, 1909 in Lake Mills, Iowa. Stegner was an American historian, novelist, short story writer, and environmentalist. He won the Pulitzer Prize in 1972 and the U.S. National Book Award in 1977. He received a B.A. at the University of Utah in 1930. He also studied at the Iowa Writers' Workshop at the University of Iowa, where he received a master's degree in 1932 and a doctorate in 1935. Stegner taught at the University of Wisconsin and Harvard University. Eventually he settled at Stanford University, where he founded the creative writing program. Stegner died on April 13, 1993.
Scope and Contents
Papers include miscellaneous files about Stanford University, the Wallace Stegner Fellowship in the Stanford University Creative Writing Program, and research and writings about Bernard De Voto.
Access Terms
De Voto, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955; Stanford University. Creative Writing Program; Stegner, Mary; Creative writing--Study and teaching.; Mormons--Utah--History.; Stanford University--History.
Collection Contents
- Four Portraits and One Subject: Bernard De Voto, by Wallace Stegner, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Stanford University related correspondence, 1944-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- History of Stanford Fellowships, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Stanford Writing Program, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Civil Liberties - Bruce Franklin, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- De Voto, DAB (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bernard De Voto - Literary History of the America West, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- De Voto's Western Adventure, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bernard De Voto and the Mormons: Three Letters, Dialogue: A Journal of Mormon Thought, 1971 Winter (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Historian by Serendipity (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Disappearance of Plot in the English Short Story: 1875-1910, by Suzanne Ferguson (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Imprint of the Stanford University Library Associates, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)